<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<test-set>	
		<topic t_id="1" t_name="Alzheimer">
		<reading-test r_id="1">
			<doc d_id="1">	
Alzheimer's DiseaseIntroductionAlzheimer's disease (AD) is a neurodegenerative disease or a disease that causes progressive damage to brain cells leading to slow but relentless mental decline.  The most common early symptoms with AD are difficulty learning and remembering new information, problems navigating familiar routes, difficulty with finding words, and deficits in multi-tasking (doing several things at once). As AD progresses, memory and spatial problems worsen and new cognitive problems arise, including deficits in understanding and expressing ideas, loss of the ability to calculate, read and write, and severe difficulties with problem-solving. Usually patients maintain their social graces but as the illness progresses behavioral symptoms including apathy, agitation, anxiety, and delusions (false beliefs) emerge. Eventually, the cognitive and behavioral problems associated with AD cause "dementia," defined as cognitive impairment severe enough to interfere with daily life activities such as work, social interactions, hobbies, or self-care. There are many diseases that cause dementia, although AD is the most common cause of dementia in older adults.                    Causes/Risk FactorsWhat are the factors that cause people to develop those neurobiological changes? Without a doubt, the most important risk is aging.  Incidence, or new cases of AD, approximately double every five years after the age of 65 years.  In the very old, (above 90), the number of people who manifest AD-like changes is extremely high, leading some to believe that if we all lived long enough we would all get AD.  How aging leads to these changes remains unknown. For some, genetic factors contribute to, or even cause development of the disease. This risk is greatest for those with a strong family history of AD, and for individuals whose family members were diagnosed with AD before age 65. Familial AD, which is inherited in an autosomal dominant pattern, is caused by mutations in the amyloid precursor protein (APP) gene on chromosome 21, the presenilin 1 gene on chromosome 14, or the presenilin 2 gene on chromosome 1. These mutations all lead to excessive production of a protein called beta amyloid (Aβ). With this genetic form of AD, if the gene is carried there is near 100% likelihood that the person will develop AD if they live beyond 60 years.  Less than 5% of AD cases are transmitted in this fashion.  A more common genetic risk is associated with the apolipoprotein gene on chromosome 19. This gene has three common variants or alleles, called APOE-e2, APOE-e3, and APOE-e4. Individuals with 1 or 2 copies of the APOE-e4 allele have a substantially increased risk for AD, whereas individuals with 1 or 2 copies of the APOE-e2 allele have decreased risk. Unlike the familial genes that cause AD, having APOE-e4 does not guarantee that you will get AD, but increases your risk substantially. In addition, having Down's syndrome, or a family history of other dementias or Parkinson's disease, also appears to increase risk.The remaining risks for developing AD appears to come from environmental factors, although the precise mechanisms by which these risk factors contribute to AD is not entirely known. Head injury is one of the most preventable environmental risk factors. Typically, head injuries are only considered risks when there is a loss of consciousness, which indicates brain trauma. Other potentially modifiable environmental risk factors include high blood pressure, high cholesterol, and diabetes, which can be reduced through diet and exercise. Diets rich in antioxidants, Vitamin E, and omega-3 fatty acids may reduce risk for AD, while diets high in fat and calories increase risk. In addition, exercise may reduce risk for AD by improving cerebrovascular health and promoting the growth of new neurons in brain regions responsible for memory.  Education is commonly considered to be a preventive factor, but the relationship between education level and AD is complex. Individuals with very high levels of education are typically diagnosed with AD less frequently and at older ages than similar individuals with less education. However, autopsy examinations show greater brain shrinkage in individuals with high education levels, which is an indication of greater progression of AD. Many researchers now believe that education and the associated intellectual strengths that come with it cannot prevent AD, but delay the diagnosis through what is referred to as "cognitive reserve," or a cognitive cushion that buffers one against showing symptoms of AD.Depression, and particularly depression that occurs first in older adulthood, has been suggested to be a risk factor. Whether or not late-life depression is a risk, or rather just an an early sign of AD is still unknown. Having depression at younger ages does not appear to be a risk factor for AD.Female gender is associated with a slightly increased risk of developing AD. It is unclear, however, whether that risk stems primarily from the tendency of women to live longer than men, which puts them at increased risk simply by virtue of their older age.ProgressionAlzheimer's disease is known for its insidious onset and slow progression. It is preceded by a stage where cognitive functioning is diminished relative to peers of a similar age and education level, but which is not sufficiently severe to merit a diagnosis of AD. This stage is sometimes called mild cognitive impairment (MCI) or mild AD; however, not everyone diagnosed with MCI will go on to develop AD. Although there are no true distinctions between different stages of the disease, these stages may be helpful in describing the disease progression. It typically takes years for a person with AD to progress from 1 stage to another, and because there are no clear demarcations between stages, there is often overlap.The medial temporal and parietal areas of the brain are typically the first areas to appear shrunken as neurons die. Shrinkage is particularly early and prominent in the hippocampi, structures that are needed for making new memories, and in the posterior parietal lobes, which are involved in spatial skills, navigation, and calculation. Later, nearly the entire brain appears shrunken, and the spaces within the brain, called ventricles, grow larger.                      Memory and spatial problems are usually the first symptoms seen and are disproportionate to problems with attention, organizing, and multi-tasking. About half of people with AD have one or more psychiatric symptoms such as depression, apathy, or insomnia in the early to moderate stages. Agitation and insomnia become more common in the moderate stages of the disease, while behavioral disturbances are most likely to emerge in the moderate to severe stages. Of note, although people with AD have pronounced cognitive problems, they typically retain social skills until they are in the moderate to severe stages. These characteristics can help differentiate between AD and other types of dementia.Impairments in activities of daily living, or basic living skills such as bathing and dressing one's self, frequently do not occur until the moderate to severe stages of the disease. Difficulties with bathing and dressing may be the first observed difficulties that occur in the moderate stage, while difficulties eating and toileting occurring more frequently in the severe stage. In addition, memory and judgment problems can impair safe self-care in the moderate to severe stages of the disease. Because AD tends to spare the motor systems until the latest stages of the disease, people with AD typically do not need wheelchairs or other movement aids as a result of the disease, although, of course, other medical problems common to aging may necessitate such devices.In the last stage of the disease, which is sometimes called the terminal stage, people are frequently cared for in institutions due to increased care demands. At this stage, people may have difficulty swallowing whole foods and thin liquids, and consequently may need to drink thickened liquids for nutrition. Tube feeding is sometimes implemented in institutions if a patient has difficulty swallowing even thickened liquids or refuses nutrition. However, tube feeding tends to be very uncomfortable and may not improve survival or reduce the risk of aspiration pneumonia 11, and so its use should be carefully considered. Reduced mobility, often leading patients to be bed-bound, increases risk for infections and bedsores. Because people with terminal stage AD have very reduced ability to make decisions and communicate, family members should be actively involved in making treatment decisions and ensuring care that is consistent with the patient's desires and values.DiagnosisA thorough evaluation, which is the best way to distinguish between AD and other neurodegenerative disorders or normal aging, can be complex and ideally requires a multi-disciplinary team of physicians, nurses, neuropsychologists, and social workers. Such an evaluation often includes:   1. a careful history, including:         1. family history of neurological disease         2. current symptoms         3. the onset and course of symptoms         4. risk factors for AD and other neurological disorders         5. medical history         6. current medications         7. drug and alcohol use         8. sleep habits         9. education level and work history   2. a neurological exam, which examines:         1. cranial nerves         2. gait         3. balance and stability         4. motor function and motor sequences         5. sensory perception and discrimination         6. reflexes   3. cognitive or neuropsychological exam, which tests:         1. verbal and nonverbal learning and memory         2. visuospatial perception and copying/drawing ability         3. speech and language skills         4. attention         5. processing speed         6. executive functioning (higher-order cognitive tasks such as mentally manipulating information, mental flexibility, response inhibition, planning, problem solving, abstraction, and judgment)         7. motor speed         8. mood   4. blood work, which looks for signs of:         1. infection         2. kidney dysfunction         3. liver dysfunction         4. B12 or folic acid deficiency         5. thyroid dysfunction         6. autoimmune disorders   5. neuroimaging, using 1 or more of the following techniques:         1. CT or MRI --- examines brain structure for places of atrophy characteristic of AD         2. PET or SPECT --- examine brain function for places of hypometabolism or hypoperfusion characteristic of AD.  This test is only recommended for patients in whom diagnosis is difficult.  After an evaluation, a person who is thought to have AD may be given a diagnosis of "probable AD," "possible AD," or "amnestic MCI."  MCI is an early stage where cognitive dysfunction is documented, but is not sufficiently severe to interfere with daily life. People with amnestic MCI show deficits primarily ---or only--- in the area of memory, and are at high risk of progressing to AD.  Probable AD is diagnosed when a person has been established to have dementia by a clinical examination and neuropsychological testing, the dementia onset was between ages 40 and 90, the person shows deficits in 2 or more cognitive domains, has progressive memory loss and other cognitive deterioration, is not delirious, and does not have other disorders that could be responsible for causing the symptoms. Possible AD is diagnosed when a person shows a slow progressive deterioration in only one cognitive area or has been diagnosed with another disorder that could produce dementia. A definitive diagnosis of AD cannot be made until the brain has been directly examined for the characteristic pathological signs of AD, which typically occurs only at autopsy. However, due to the amount of research that has been conducted on AD, when pre-autopsy diagnoses are made after a thorough evaluation, diagnoses have a high degree of accuracy.There are many causes for dementia that are not due to AD, including other degenerative conditions such as frontotemporal dementia, vascular dementia, Parkinsonian-dementia and medical conditions such as B12 deficiency. Accurate diagnosis is the key to effective therapy.  TreatmentOnce a diagnosis of AD has been made, treatment of the disease should be considered.  Treatment has many components and should focus around the following:o       Symptomatic therapy with medicationso       Treatment of difficult behaviors with medicationso       Treatment of difficult behaviors with changes in the environmento       Organizing finances, legal issues, advanced directiveso       Making sure that the caregiver maintains his or her health Symptomatic therapy with medications: Currently there are two types of medications approved for the treatment of AD, cholinesterase inhibitors and NMDA antagonists.  Cholinesterase inhibitors work by increasing the brain's level of acetylcholine, and they are the mainstay of AD treatment.  The three cholinesterase inhibitors used in medical practice are Donepezil (Aricept), Rivastigmine (Exelon), and Galantamine (Razadyne).  When these medications work they typically lead to mild improvements in attention, thinking, and memory.  Generally, patients on these medications do better than patients not taking them.  Donepezil, Rivastigmine and Galantamine are all approved for treatment of mild to moderate AD, while Donepezil is also approved for treatment of severe disease.  The side effects of these medications are low, with gastrointestinal upset and sleep disturbance the major concerns.  When AD is diagnosed the patient should be started on one of the cholinesterase inhibitors.  Memantine (Namenda) is approved for the treatment of moderate to severe AD and it works by blocking areas in the brain that are overexcited by a neurotransmitter called glutamate.  Memantine can be added to a cholinesterase inhibitor, or used alone, and has few side effects. None of these medications leads to miraculous improvements, but even subtle changes in patients can be a big positive for caregivers.  New medications designed to slow the aggregation of Aβ are under active study and may have more impressive effects than the current generation of compounds.  Treatment of Difficult Behaviors with Medications or Environmental Changes: Treating agitated or unwanted behaviors is extremely difficult and should always begin by thinking about why the behavior has emerged.  AD patients may not be able to explain how they feel.  Pain associated with a urinary infection, tooth decay, or back problems can manifest as agitation or confusion.  Similarly, depressed mood can trigger difficult behaviors.  Therefore, a careful medical evaluation is important if behavior has changed.  Additionally, review of possible environment triggers is needed.  Sleep in the daytime will often mean that the patient stays awake at night.  Lack of exercise will increase the likelihood that the patient will become irritable or agitated.  Overstimulation and big changes in the environment often precipitate difficult behaviors. Medications for these behaviors have limited value and often make things worse rather than better.  Sometimes antidepressant compounds will smooth out difficult periods.  Antipsychotic and anxiolytic medications have significant toxicities and are typically most effective when they are used in low doses for limited periods of time. Organizing finances, legal issues, advanced directives: Thinking ahead is a key to effective caregiving.  AD is a continually changing illness and what works at one stage may not work later on.  Eventually patients lose their ability to make good decisions and the family will need to consider wills, financial decision-making, and advanced directives for health care at the earliest possible stage. Included in this planning is the designation of a health care proxy --- a person who is chosen to make medical decisions once the patient is unable to participate in these him or herself.Making sure that the caregiver maintains his or her health:  Caregiving is one of the most difficult tasks that we will ever face.  Maintaining good health and good spirits is essential.  Exercise programs, time alone, daycare, sitters, respite programs, and support groups can make caregiving less difficult and should be considered at all stages of the illness.  The Alzheimer's Association can aid families in accessing health support.  Practical tips for living with ADPeople may feel overwhelmed after being diagnosed with AD. Some find it helpful to read about the disease, so that they understand their diagnosis and know better what to expect as the disease progresses. Understanding the disease and prognosis can help you plan for your future and make important decisions, such as creating an advance health care directive, and making decisions about how and where you want to live. It is also helpful to have a trusted friend or family member with you at your medical appointments. This person can help you in a number of ways. He or she can ask your doctor important questions, help you remember the information your doctor provides you, help plan future appointments or make other relevant plans, provide emotional support, and help you get to and from your appointments.In addition, AD affects more people than those diagnosed with it --- it affects family members and other loved ones. Behavioral problems are typically more difficult for caregivers and other loved ones than are memory problems. Here are several behavioral issues that frequently arise with AD, and ways that may help deal with them.    * Suspicion or paranoia: People with AD sometimes become suspicious of others. If you are the subject of that suspicion, it can be hurtful and confusing. It is helpful to understand that people with AD frequently become suspicious because they cannot keep track of things as well as they used to; when they move something, they often cannot remember that they have done so. It therefore seems to them that their environment, and the valuable things in it, changes inexplicably, and so they make sense of these changes by thinking that other people must be stealing from them. This thought typically has nothing to do with how trustworthy a loved one has been, and it is usually the person or people closest to the AD patient who is blamed. Rather than defending yourself, or getting emotional if this happens, you can help the person look for whatever has been misplaced. Or, if possible, you can replace it.    * Forgotten bills: People with AD can have a difficult time paying bills, keeping track of their finances, and otherwise managing their money. They can also be at risk for elder financial abuse. Caregivers often find their lives improve dramatically when they take over handling the finances, and no longer have to worry about whether or not the bills are being paid. Being involved with finances also can help prevent elder financial abuse, or enable any scams or fraud to be quickly recognized and remedied.    * Personality changes: Although personality change is typically not as striking in AD as it is in some other types of dementias, it is not uncommon. People with AD can become agitated, confused, depressed, anxious, stubborn, or needy. Some personality or emotional changes, such as depression, can be treated pharmacologically. Sometimes, it is helpful to recognize that personality changes can be the result of poorer cognitive skills --- that when people cannot communicate their thoughts and feelings well verbally, they communicate through actions. Identifying "triggers," or the preceding events or circumstances, of unwanted behavior can help you understand what may be distressing to the person. Once you understand this, you can modify the environment appropriately. In addition, blame the disease for the distressing behavior or personality changes, rather than blaming the person.    * Fluctuating symptoms: One of the most confusing things to many caregivers is that a loved one with AD can sometimes seem to remember things, or be able to perform certain tasks, and other times cannot. This is normal, and it is part of the disease process. Although it may seem that a person is "faking" when their symptoms are worse, or that they should be able to do something all the time if they can do it some of the time, neither of these ideas are true. People with AD truly do have fluctuating abilities. Blaming the disease for these frustrating and confusing moments, rather than blaming the person with AD for not always being able to do things, is very helpful. It is also helpful to simply recognize that symptoms, including cognitive abilities, fluctuate over the course of the day and change over time.    * Wandering: Individuals with AD often leave their home to take a walk or with the intention of going somewhere, but become disoriented or lost. It's not unusual for caregivers to become panicked when they realize that the person with AD is gone. To prevent wandering, you can affix a bell to the door, so that you are alerted when the person with AD is trying to leave, or post a sign on the door that says, "Do not open". There are also steps you can take to help find the person who has wandered. First, you can have the person wear an ID bracelet with the person's name and your phone number. Second, you can enroll the person in the Alzheimer's Association's Safe Return program, which provides an ID bracelet or pendant, a "community support network to help reunite the lost person with his or her caregiver," and 24-hour wandering or medical emergency response services. Third, you can call the police. Try not to be angry or overly emotional when you find your loved one after he or she has wandered --- this will only be upsetting, and not helpful. In addition to these steps, it may be helpful to take walks with the person during the daytime, to enable him or her to get exercise while giving yourself the security of knowing where he or she is.In addition to these suggestions, there are a number of organizations that can provide help. These organizations can provide answers to your questions, support groups to help cope with emotional distress and practical difficulties, and resources to help you learn more about AD and cope with the diagnosis. 
			</doc>
				<q  q_id="1" >
					<q_str>Which medical disorder first described in 1866 can increase the risk of developing Alzheimer's disease?</q_str>
					<answer a_id='1' >APOE-e2</answer>
					<answer a_id='2' >APOE-e3</answer>
					<answer a_id='3' >APOE-e4</answer>
					<answer a_id='4'  correct="Yes">Down's syndrome</answer>
					<answer a_id='5' >Parkinson's disease</answer>
				</q>
				<q  q_id="2" >
					<q_str>Why is the short-term memory affected more severely in the early stages of the disease than the long-term memory?</q_str>
					<answer a_id='1'  correct="Yes">because the disease first attacks the hippocampus</answer>
					<answer a_id='2' >because the disease first attacks the posterior parietal lobes</answer>
					<answer a_id='3' >because the ventricles increase</answer>
					<answer a_id='4' >because the space in the brain increases</answer>
					<answer a_id='5' >because the short-term memory is smaller</answer>
				</q>
				<q  q_id="3" >
					<q_str>What type of diet may reduce the risk of Alzheimer's disease?</q_str>
					<answer a_id='1' >a diet that contains a lot of sugary foods such as sweets and cakes</answer>
					<answer a_id='2' >a diet that contains foods with a high fat content such as chips and crisps</answer>
					<answer a_id='3' >any diet that is low in fruits and vegetables
</answer>
					<answer a_id='4'  correct="Yes">a diet that contains cold-water oily fish, fruit and vegetables</answer>
					<answer a_id='5' >a diet that is mainly based on fatty meat</answer>
				</q>
				<q  q_id="4" >
					<q_str>Why are feeding tubes not always recommended for Alzheimer's patients who have difficulties with swallowing?</q_str>
					<answer a_id='1' >because the type of food needed by Alzheimer's patients can't be supplied via a feeding tube</answer>
					<answer a_id='2' >because the risk is too high that Alzheimer's sufferers will choke on the tube</answer>
					<answer a_id='3'  correct="Yes">because the tube may cause discomfort and does not avoid pneumonia</answer>
					<answer a_id='4' >because with Alzheimer's patients it is often difficult to insert a feeding tube</answer>
					<answer a_id='5' >because the feeding tube can distort other examination results</answer>
				</q>
				<q  q_id="5" >
					<q_str>When can Alzheimer's disease be diagnosed with absolute certainty?</q_str>
					<answer a_id='1' >when the first symptoms develop</answer>
					<answer a_id='2'  correct="Yes">after the patient's death</answer>
					<answer a_id='3' >only during the medium stage of the disease</answer>
					<answer a_id='4' >by means of a blood test even before the first symptoms</answer>
					<answer a_id='5' >in the final stages by means of neurological tests</answer>
				</q>
				<q  q_id="6" >
					<q_str>Does the author recommend medication to treat behavioural problems?</q_str>
					<answer a_id='1' >yes, because there are a number of good medications without side effects, e.g. Aricept</answer>
					<answer a_id='2' >yes, because the positive effects outweight the negative side effects</answer>
					<answer a_id='3' >no, because there are no medications that can treat behavioural problems</answer>
					<answer a_id='4' >no, because the available medications haven't yet been sufficiently tested</answer>
					<answer a_id='5'  correct="Yes">not really, because medications don't address the causes and often have severe side effects</answer>
				</q>
				<q  q_id="7" >
					<q_str>Why should caregivers take regular walks with the patients?</q_str>
					<answer a_id='1' >because otherwise there is a danger that patients will lose their mobility</answer>
					<answer a_id='2' >to give patients the opportunity to familiarise themselves with their neighbourhood</answer>
					<answer a_id='3' >because exercise increases the brain's oxygen supply and can thus improve memory</answer>
					<answer a_id='4'  correct="Yes">because it makes patients less irritable and reduces the likelihood that they will take a walk on their own</answer>
					<answer a_id='5' >because the patient's memory can be trained and improve due to the impressions obtained during the walk</answer>
				</q>
				<q  q_id="8" >
					<q_str>How do Alzheimer's medications work?</q_str>
					<answer a_id='1' >they only treat depression which often occurs together with Alzheimer's</answer>
					<answer a_id='2'  correct="Yes">they raise the amount of acetylchonline in the brain</answer>
					<answer a_id='3' >they treat a lack of B12</answer>
					<answer a_id='4' >they increase the level of cholinesterase in the brain</answer>
					<answer a_id='5' >they make it easier for patients to sleep</answer>
				</q>
				<q  q_id="9" >
					<q_str>Why does the author recommend that caregivers take over handling the patient's finances at an early stage?</q_str>
					<answer a_id='1' >because the treatment can be extremely costly and thus requires good investment decisions</answer>
					<answer a_id='2'  correct="Yes">because patients can lose their ability to deal with their finances very quickly</answer>
					<answer a_id='3' >because it is crucial for the recovery process that patients are not burdened with financial decisions</answer>
					<answer a_id='4' >because expenses have to be minimised to make sure that enough is saved to finance a place in a care home</answer>
					<answer a_id='5' >because the government requires that in the case of Alzheimer's, a legal guardian is appointed early on</answer>
				</q>
				<q  q_id="10" >
					<q_str>How should one react when one is accused by an Alzheimer's patient of stealing valuables?</q_str>
					<answer a_id='1' >one should show one's emotions and defend oneself</answer>
					<answer a_id='2' >one should call the police immediately</answer>
					<answer a_id='3' >one should distract the patient with stories from the past</answer>
					<answer a_id='4' >one should admit everything to avoid upsetting the patient unnecessarily</answer>
					<answer a_id='5'  correct="Yes">one should stay calm and help the patient find the missing item</answer>
				</q>
		</reading-test>
	</topic>
</test-set>
